CAROLINE BROWNLEE

Full Stack Software Engineer

PERSONAL PROFILE

Enthusiastic full stack developer with more than 10 years' experience as a writer and editor. The years I've spent using my mind creatively will benefit us as a team when designing products and delivering new features. My keen attention to detail and strong communication skills will aid in documentation and interacting with project stakeholders, project management, and development teams.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Founder of Mom's Without Borders: Local nonprofit with a mission to help mothers and their children with unexpected financial needs and assistance; 65 members
- Founder of Sumner County Homeschoolers: Nonprofit community outreach group with a mission to connect local home educators and their families to social and enrichment opportunities; 942 members

PROJECTS

Print Destroyer

Single page CRUD application that allows the. administrator to create a database of artwork, register new customers, and allows customers to create a wishlist. Built using React, styled with CSS/Flexbox, utilizes Firebase for photo storage, and JSON server to store data to a local API.

I, Joseph

A community outreach application that connects members to volunteer opportunities. Users can submit a form to open new opportunities as needs arise. Users can also view a list of open opportunities to check out and complete. Built using Python/Django, JavaScript, CSS, and SQL.

GET IN TOUCH



615 - 681 - 7778



github.com/CarolineBrownlee

linkedin.com/in/caroline-brownlee/



brownleecaroline@gmail.com

https://caroline-madison.com/

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer

Nashville Software School, 2019 - 2020

- Built single page CRUD applications on individual and group projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Created ERD's to determine database dependencies
- \bullet Designed signal flow wireframes to illustrate functionality across components
- Wrote user stories
- · Pitched application stories and features to a senior development team
- · Utilized JSON to access and manipulate data from external and local APIs
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Used GitHub for project management and source control on individual and group projects
- Utilized agile scrum methodologies for project management
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Queried and exposed databases using SQL and ORM to build server side applications in Python and Django
- \cdot Team lead and participant on group sprints to create front and back end applications using DjangoREST framework to build APIs

Creative Writer

Caroline Brownlee, Current

- Created several blogs over fifteen years that engaged an audience
- Published articles in online publications
- · Mastered creating an online presence and continual content production

Educator

Caroline Brownlee, 2004 - 2019

- Wrote lesson plans and taught three children preschool through elementary ages
- · Conducted research into curriculum options
- Matched individual learning styles with curriculum
- · Planned and led educational field trips
- · Established and led enrichment activities to facilitate learning
- Managed budgets
- Established a local Girl Scout chapter that required handling budgets, sales and distribution, writing and conducting lesson plans, and organizing community service projects

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, 2019 - 2020

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ An intense, nine month, full-stack web development bootcamp that focuses on individual and group projects